They have one shot to get back home.
Madagascar 3: Europe's Most Wanted is a animation,
family, comedy film directed by Eric Darnell.
Animal pals Alex, Marty, Melman, and Gloria are still trying to
make it back to New York's Central Park Zoo.
They are forced to take a detour to Europe to find the penguins and
chimps who broke the bank at a Monte Carlo casino.
When French animal-control officer Capitaine Chantel DuBois picks up their scent,
Alex and company are forced to hide out in a traveling circus.
Alex (voice), played by Ben Stiller.
Marty (voice), played by Chris Rock.
Melman (voice), played by David Schwimmer.
Gloria (voice), played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
Captain Chantel DuBois (voice), played by Frances McDormand.
Julien (voice), played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
Madagascar 3: Europe's Most Wanted is a 2012 American animated comedy film directed by Eric
Darnell, Conrad Vernon and Tom McGrath, and written by Darnell and Noah Baumbach.
The third in the Madagascar film series, it was
produced by DreamWorks Animation.
The film features Ben Stiller, Chris Rock, David Schwimmer, Jada Pinkett Smith, Sacha Baron Cohen, Cedric the Entertainer, Andy Richter, McGrath, Chris Miller, Christopher Knights,
John DiMaggio and Vernon reprising their roles from the previous films, with Jessica Chastain, Bryan Cranston, Martin Short and Frances McDormand joining the cast.
In the film, the main characters—a party of animals from the Central Park Zoo whose adventures have already taken them to Madagascar and Africa—attempt to return to
New York City and find themselves traveling across Europe with a circus while being pursued by the villainous head of Monaco's animal control service.
DreamWorks Animation announced the third film in August 2008,
three months before the release of the second film.
As with the previous films in the franchise, the
score was composed by Hans Zimmer.
Madagascar 3: Europe's Most Wanted premiered out of competition at the 2012 Cannes Film Festival on May 18,
2012, and was theatrically released in the United States on June 8 by Paramount Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews and was the eighth highest-grossing film of
2012, with a gross of $746 million against a budget of $145 million.
A spin-off, Penguins of Madagascar, was released in 2014.
The film explores themes of friendship, circus, lion, zoo, hippopotamus.
The tone is lighthearted.